Rockwell Kent papers 4079547
Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Series VII: Bookplates
  - Printed misc.:
    - American Society of Bookplate Collectors and Designers. (Box 25)
      - Year book 1969/1970. [Pasadena, CA.] the society, 1972. 26p.(Vol. 35):
        - p.1-7 is Dan Burne Jones: "Genesis of a Rockwell Kent bookplate design "[Jeanette Clarke]. (Box 25)
        - p.[27] is H.M. Gellrer bookplate. (Box 25)
    - Vanity Fair, p. 84:, April 1929
      - "bookplate designs by Rockwell Kent…" (Box 25)
- Series VIII: Exhibitions
  - ACA Galleries …, 1989
    - printed announcement (Box 26)
    - videotape cassette (Box 26)
  - American Institute of Graphic Arts …, 1926
    - printed copy (Box 26)
  - The Art Gallery of Toronto:
    - "Cold feet and warm hearts in Greenland" lecture by Rockwell Kent (Box 26)
      - announcement (Box 26)
      - printed copy (Box 26)
  - Associated American Artists …, 1975
    - printed invitation (Box 26)
  - Associated American Artists …, 1987
    - 2 printed catalogs (Box 26)
  - Bowdoin College Museum of Art: Rockwell Kent: the early years. [Brunswick, ME.] Bowdoin College, 1960. 1 vol. (catalogue of 60 paintings by Rockwell Kent) Carnegie Institute (Pittsburgh, PA.): "Paintings by Rockwell Kent"-catalogue:
    - printed (Box 26)
    - leaflet (Box 26)
  - The Center for Music, Drama and Art (Lake Placid NY) …, 1975
    - 4 printed items (Box 26)
  - The Center for Music, Drama and Art (Lake Placid NY) …, 1977
    - printed catalog (Box 26)
  - Christie's East …, 1995
    - printed catalog (Box 26)
  - A Collectors List, Inc. (Rockville Centre NY) … n.d.:
    - mimeographed sales catalog (Box 26)
  - Columbus Museum of Art … 7 items Daniel Gallery: "The Newfoundland paintings and drawings of Rockwell Kent"-catalogue:, 1985
    - printed leaflet (Box 26)
  - The Digressionists-Fifth Exhibition, 2, March1911
    - printed program, 8p. in portfolio (Box 26)
  - East River Savings Bank …, 1975
    - printed catalog (Box 26)
  - Gallery of Modern Masters (Washington DC) …, 1937
    - Clipping (Box 26)
  - The Harbor Gallery (Cold Spring Harbor, NY.)-announcement:
    - printed copy (Box 26)
  - Kennedy & Co.: "The Hogarth, Jr. Series"-announcement:
    - printed copies, 2p. (Box 26)
  - Knoedler & Co.:
    - "Alaska drawings," 1-12 March1919-catalogue: (Box 26)
    - pencil drafts oversize pencil drafts, 3p. printed copy clipping (Box 26)
  - Knoedler & Co.: (Box 26)
    - "Alaska paintings"-announcement: (Box 26)
    - ink draft on printed copy printed copies, 2p. (Box 26)
  - The Joint Distribution Committee … "Rare Book Auction" …, 1938 (Box 26)
  - The Lakeside Press (Chicago): "The Christening of 'Moby Dick,'" 5, December 1930
    - printed invitation, 3p. (Box 26)
  - The Lakeside Press (Chicago):
    - An exhibition of contemporary American book illustration...Chicago, R.R. Donnelley & Sons, 1930. 1 vol. Landscape in Maine, a sesquicentennial exhibition. N.p., Maine Federation of Women's Clubs, The Maine State Commission on the Arts and Humanities, Colby College, Bowdoin College, and the University of Maine at Orono [1970] 128p.:p.84-85 is Kent's Cranberrying Monhegan., 1820-1970 (Box 26)
  - Larcada Gallery-announcement and catalogue:
    - printed copy (Box 26)
  - Larcada Gallery …, 1966
    - printed catalog (Box 26)
  - Larcada Gallery, 7-25 November 1972-announcement:
    - 2 printed copies (Box 26)
  - Larcada Gallery …, 1974
    - 2 mimeographed catalogs (Box 26)
  - Larcada Gallery …, 1977
    - mimeographed auction catalog (Box 26)
  - Littlecote Galleries, Inc. (Utica, NY.): "Annual Spring Exhibit"-catalogue:
    - printed copy (Box 26)
  - Mitchell Museum (Mount Vernon IL) …, 1976
    - 2 items (Box 27)
  - The New York Public Library … n.d.:
    - mimeographed news release (Box 27)
  - Parke-Bernet Galleries: "Auction of drawings by Rockwell Kent," 4 May 1972-catalogue:
    - 3 printed copies (Box 27)
  - Plattsburgh State University /SUNY Plattsburgh …:
    - 13 items (Box 27)
  - The Pynson Printers: "Candide:
    - original drawings"-announcement: printed copy (handcolored) (Box 27)
  - The Pynson Printers: "Later bookplates & marks of Rockwell Kent" …, 1937
    - 3 printed copies (Box 27)
  - Santa Barbara Museum of Art …, 1985
    - "An Enkindled Eye"; the Paintings of Rockwell Kent, June 29-Sept. 1, 1985 (Box 27)
  - Swarthmore College …, 1982
    - "The Many Faceted Rockwell Kent", Jan. 5-March 31, 1982 (Box 27)
      With invitation for reception on Jan. 21, 1982, with talk by William J. Spangler
  - Tregoning Fine Art, Inc. …, 1988
    - 6 items (Box 27)
  - Weyhe Gallery: "Drawings for Moby Dick"-announcement:
    - printed leaflet (Box 27)
  - Weyhe Gallery: "Water-colors of Ireland," 4-26 March 1927-announcement:
    - printed copy (Box 27)
  - Weyhe Gallery: "Woodcuts and lithographs by Rockwell Kent"-catalogue:
    - printed copy. (Box 27)
  - Wien Fine Art …, 1993
    - printed catalog (Box 27)
  - Wildenstein & Co.: "Know and defend America"-announcement:
    - ink draft (Box 27)
    - ink lettering (Box 27)
    - ink lettering (red and black) (Box 27)
    - ink and pencil lettering, 2p. (Box 27)
    - ink sketch (Box 27)
    - pencil drafts, 4p. (Box 27)
    - pencil lettering, 5p. (Box 27)
    - printed copies (2) (Box 27)
  - Wildenstein & Co.:
    - "Know and defend America"-catalogue: (Box 27)
      - p.1 proof (Box 27)
      - p.5 ink draft (red and black) (Box 27)
      - p.5 proof (Box 27)
      - p.9 proof (Box 27)
      - p.11 proof (Box 27)
      - p.15 proof (Box 27)
      - ink drafts, 2p. (Box 27)
      - 2 pencil mock-up copies (Box 27)
    - "Know and defend America"-catalogue: printed copy (Box 27)
    - "Know and defend America"-clipping Wildenstein & Co. (Box 27)
    - "Know and defend America"-misc. (Box 27)
    - "Retrospective;" oversize printed sign card (Mapcase 13V-F-06)
    - Announcements: 3 printed copies The Workshop Gallery of L. Calapai (Glencoe IL) … printed catalog, 1974 (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Materials: (Box 27)
      - Tregoning Fine Art, Inc. (Box 27)
        - Prints by Edmund Blampied, and Rockwell Kent from the Leona E. Prasse Collection, 1988 (Box 27)
          Two copies with realted notes and broadsides
- Series VIX: Magazine Illustration
  - Adventure:
    - "Arizony" by C.E. Kilbourne: proof (lettering) (Box 28)
    - "Ashton's memorial;" ink sketch (Box 28)
    - "Big business in Bombay;" ink sketches proof (corrected) (Box 28)
    - oversize border: ink sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - "The camp-fire;" proof (Box 28)
    - "Cockades" by Meade Minnigerode:
      - proof cover: (Box 28)
      - ink sketch (Box 28)
      - watercolor sketch (Box 28)
      - oversize watercolor sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - "Cyrano de Bergerac;" ink sketch (Box 28)
    - "The dubasher" by Captain Mansfield: proof (lettering) (Box 28)
    - "Dandyfunk" by Norma Springer: proof (lettering) (Box 28)
    - "Heat;" ink sketches (Box 28)
    - "Hellbuster Doova" by Captain Dingle:
      - ink drafts, 2p. (Box 28)
      - proof (Box 28)
    - Maps: ink sketches, 12p. (Box 28)
    - Oversize maps: ink sketches, 3p. (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - "Marshal Pop Carver" by Donald Hough: proof (Box 28)
    - "Miracles;" ink sketches (Box 28)
    - "On getting acquainted;" ink sketch (Box 28)
    - "The patriot's progress or the long road" by Wm. Hogarth, Jr. & Atreus (Box 28)
    - Hargadine:
      - proofs, 2p. (Box 28)
      - oversize proofs, 3p. (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - "Play acting for gents" (Box 28)
    - "In this corner" (Box 28)
    - "A military interlude;" ink sketches (Box 28)
    - "The rub o' the saddle;" ink sketches (Box 28)
    - "Rusudan;" ink sketches (Box 28)
    - "Scavengers of the surf ..." by Harry R. Peterson: proof (Box 28)
    - "Sea of the ravens;" ink sketches (Box 28)
    - "The silver circle" by Lyman Bryson: proof (Box 28)
    - "Smoking seas;" ink sketch (Box 28)
    - "That cartwheel stallion" by Edwin Hunt Hoover: proof (Box 28)
    - "Three thieves;" ink sketch and proof (corrected) (Box 28)
    - vignettes: ink sketches and proof (Box 28)
    - oversize "Wastrel;" ink sketches (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - "Wastrel," "Jim Clancy shoves off;" ink sketches (Box 28)
    - "The well of bitter waters" by George Surdez: (Box 28)
      - proof (Box 28)
      - proof (corrected) (Box 28)
      - ink sketches: 2p. (Box 28)
      - oversize 1p. (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
      - pencil and ink drafts (Box 28)
      - pencil drafts, 3p. (Box 28)
  - Architecture and building:
    - "Clients vs. architect a plea" by Tom Thumbtack:
      - proof (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - "The cornerstone" by Tom Thumbtack: ink sketches (Box 28)
    - oversize cover: proof (Box 28)
    - "The repeal of the Tarsney Act" by Tom Thumbtack: ink sketches (Box 28)
    - oversize "Tom Thumbtack slave driver;" ink sketch (Box 28)
    - proof (Box 28)
    - various pages, 23 items (Box 28)
  - Art in America. no.4, 1961.
    - May or, A. Hyatt:
      - "A creative suggestion: stamps designed by fine artists." p.[38] (Box 28)
      - Asgaard postage stamp: (Box 28)
      - ink sketch (with photostat) (Box 28)
      - ink sketch-white ink on black and green proof (Box 28)
      - lettering (ink) (Box 28)
      - lettering (pencil), 3p. (Box 28)
      - lettering (pencil and ink), 2p. (Box 28)
      - pencil draft (Box 28)
      - proof-black, 2p. (Box 28)
      - proof-black (illus. only), 3p. (Box 28)
      - proof-gray, 2p. (Box 28)
      - proof-gray and black, 2p. (Box 28)
    - Asgaard air mail stamp (not used):
      - pencil drafts, 5p. (Box 28)
      - pencil draft (Box 28)
    - "All men are brothers" postage stamp (not used):
      - pencil drafts, 5p. (Box 28)
    - Nirvana/Utopia postage stamp (not used):
      - pencil drafts, 4p. (Box 28)
  - Blackjack:
    - ink drafts, 2p. (Box 28)
    - ink sketch (Box 28)
    - oversize ink sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - pencil drafts, 6p. (Box 28)
    - oversize pencil drafts, 17p. (Box 28)
    - proofs, 5p. (Box 28)
  - The Blue Mouse. Volume I, Nos. 1 & 2, 1906. [Unpublished]
    - Illustrated autograph manuscript, 117p.
      - (Manuscript text in Kent's hand with 57 pages of illustrations, including ink sketches, watercolor drawings, and pencil and pastel drawings by Kent using several pseudonyms. This was a collaborative effort of the 24-yearold Kent and his friend James Gillespie Blaine Ewing. The two produced this holograph periodical in an edition of two copies for each number. The copies were for the only subscribers: their mothers. The text is presumably a collaborative effort by Ewing and Kent and includes poems, song lyrics, short stories, a novella, and various parodies of advertisements, news stories, letters from readers, etc. This is Mrs Charles Ewing's copy. Binding: Boards, detached but present, with watercolor drawings by Kent. Modern half black morocco folding-case, spine gilt-lettered and with image of the Blue Mouse on his throne in variously colored morocco onlays (Box 29)
  - Bookman:
    - oversize ink sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
  - The Colophon:
    - cover: pencil draft (Box 30)
    - trademark device (Box 30)
    - pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 30)
    - "An unpublished drawing;" proof (Box 30)
  - Cosmopolitan, April 1934.
    - Hemingway, Ernest:
      - One trip across.
        - oversize ink and tempera sketch (blue and black) (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
        - oversize ink and tempera sketch (orange and black) (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
        - oversize opening pages: pencil draft (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
        - oversize pencil drafts, 2p. (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
  - Country Gentleman. cover: pencil draft (Box 30)
  - Creative Art. ink sketches (Box 30)
  - Delineator. 1926. ink sketch (Box 30)
  - The Delta Kappa Epsilon Quarterly., 1911
    - cover: pencil draft (Box 30)
    - cover: proofs, 3p. (Box 30)
  - Demcourier.
    - cover: pencil drafts, 5p. (Box 30)
    - pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 30)
    - ink draft (Box 30)
    - "Rockwell Kent issue," vol. vi, #10, 2 printed copies, October 1937 (Box 30)
  - Esquire. ink sketch (Box 30)
  - Fraternal outlook:
    - cover (1943): pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 30)
    - oversize cover (1943): pencil drafts, 2p. (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - "We hold these truths;" pencil drafts, 3p. (Box 30)
    - article on Rockwell Kent, vol. 3, #3, printed copy, March1941 (Box 30)
  - Harper's Weekly. "Roosevelticus;" ink sketch (Box 30)
  - Das Hildegartenbuch. See: Book illustration
  - The Hound and Horn:
    - cover: ink and pencil sketches, 2p. (Box 30)
    - oversize cover: ink drafts and printed copy (3p. framed in one mounting) (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
  - Junior Red Cross Journal. oversize cover: pencil draft (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
  - Lantern. cover: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 30)
  - McCall's. May 1934.
    - See: Titled drawings, etc.: The clinic.
  - Mainstream:
    - colophon: ink sketch (Box 30)
    - "My God! Can that be the American EagleÀ" printed illustration with his article (Box 30)
    - "My gift to the Soviet people", Vol. 14, No. 4, p. 36-41., April 1961 (Box 30)
  - Makio:
    - "Activities;" ink sketch (Box 30)
    - "Administration;" ink sketch (Box 30)
    - "Athletics;" ink sketch (Box 30)
    - "Organizations;" ink sketch (Box 30)
    - [school activities]: pencil drafts, 3p. (Box 30)
  - The Modern School.
    - cover: proof (Box 30)
    - pencil draft (Box 30)
    - initial letters: proofs, 2p. (Box 30)
    - initial letters: pencil drafts, 12p. (Box 30)
    - initial letters: ink and pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 30)
    - Vol. VI, #6-7, printed copy, June -July 1919 (Box 30)
  - New Masses:
    - cover: pencil draft (Box 30)
    - cover: printed copy, 3p. (Box 30)
  - The New World Review:
    - See: Titled drawings, etc.: Enormous new machines make men master over nature
  - New York Tribune Magazine:
    - oversize "The front row kept up a semblance of attention;" ink sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - oversize "I swore by sun and moon and stars," "We had a grip," "And it was real beer;" (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - ink sketches (Box 30)
    - "I"-initial letter: ink sketch (Box 30)
    - "L"-initial letter: ink sketch (Box 30)
    - oversize "The lamps shone ...;" ink sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - "N"-initial letter: ink sketch (Box 30)
    - "The neighbors" (initial letter "C"): ink sketch (Box 30)
    - "The other woman;" ink sketch (Box 30)
    - oversize "The other woman;" ink sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - oversize "Our hazing was, for the most part, harmless;" ink sketch (Box 30)
    - "Pretty P ..." by George S. Chappell: ink sketch (Box 30)
    - "Q"-initial letter: ink sketch (Box 30)
    - "A short college course" by George S. Chappell: ink lettering (Box 30)
    - "T"-initial letter: ink sketch ink sketches, 5p. (Box 30)
    - oversize ink sketches, 10p. (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - "For men only: a handbook for husbands;" printed copy (Box 30)
  - Ordinance Sergeant:
    - cover: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 31)
    - oversize cover: pencil draft (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
  - Puck:
    - oversize "New Year, New Year ..." (1920): (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - ink sketch ink sketch ink sketch (1917) (Box 31)
  - The Quarterly Journal of the Library of Congress. January 1978. printed copy with 11 illustrations by Kent (Box 31)
  - Rights (National Emergency Civil Liberties Commission), vol. xviii, #1, June 1971. "Rockwell Kent issue;" printed copy (Box 31)
  - Scribners:
    - cover: "June ;" ink sketch (Box 31)
    - cover: "November ;" ink sketch (Box 31)
    - cover: pencil draft (Box 31)
    - "Thomas E. Dewey;" ink sketch pencil draft (Box 31)
    - oversize watercolor sketch (1926) (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
  - This week magazine:
    - pencil draft, 2p. (Box 31)
    - oversize pencil sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - clipping: [volcano, 24 March1940] (Box 31)
  - Time. (portfolio) oversize pencil sketches, 7p. (Box 31)
  - Vanity Fair:
    - oversize "Pill Box Theatre;" ink sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - ink and wash sketch (Box 31)
    - oversize ink sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - ink sketches for "The ballad of Yukon Jake" (1921), see: Book illustration: Paramore, Edward. The ballad ... (Box 31)
    - pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 31)
    - See also: Advertising: Marcus and Company (Jewelers)
    - clippings, 4p. (Box 31)
  - Wings: the Literary Guild Magazine:
    - cover design: ink and blue wash sketch (Box 31)
    - cover design: pencil draft (Box 31)
    - cover design: pencil draft and ink draft (Box 31)
    - Vol.4, #12, printed copy (contains: "The making of an artist" by R.K., p.6-11, and cover illus.), December 1930 (Box 31)
  - Names of magazines are not known:
    - "The amours of Faust ..." by Rockwell Kent-title: ink lettering (Box 31)
    - [angel by Hogarth, Jr.]:
      - ink sketch (Box 31)
      - pencil draft (Box 31)
    - "Un diner a deux ..." by George S. Chappell: ink and pencil draft (Box 31)
    - [farmer]:
      - ink and pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 31)
      - red and black paint and pencil draft (Box 31)
    - oversize "Gulliver at Lilliput;" ink sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - "His better self":
      - ink and pencil drafts, 3p. (Box 31)
      - pencil drafts, 6p. (Box 31)
    - oversize "The morning smile;" ink sketches (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - "The poet's pact or the fashionable Faust ..." by Wm. Hogarth, Jr. and George S. Chappell-heading for chapter I:
      - pencil draft (Box 31)
      - watercolor draft (Box 31)
    - Vignettes:
      - ink sketches, 3p. (Box 31)
      - proofs, 2p. (Box 31)
    - illus. by Hogarth Jr.:
      - ink and pencil drafts, 7p. (Box 31)
      - ink drafts, 4p. (Box 31)
      - ink sketches, 9p. (Box 31)
      - oversize ink sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - Illus. by Hogarth, Jr.:
      - pencil and watercolor draft (Mapcase 13V-F--6-08)
      - pencil drafts, 40p. (Box 31)
      - oversize watercolor sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - oversize ink and pencil sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - oversize ink draft (black and green) (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - ink sketch (Box 31)
    - oversize ink sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - oversize pencil draft (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - oversize pencil sketches, 2p. (Mapcase 13V-F-06-08)
    - misc., 2p. (Box 31)
    - "The newer Aesop;" clipping (Box 31)
- Series X: Posters
  - oversize American Bible Society: watercolor and ink sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-09)
  - The American Cancer Society: pencil sketch (Box 32)
  - The American Red Cross: "Puppet Theatre#Vaudevi[lle#Ex]traordinary…: pencil draft (Box 32)
  - American Rescue Corps:
    - pencil draft (Box 32)
    - oversize pencil draft (Mapcase 13V-F-09)
  - [Anti-Axis posters]:
    - ink and pencil (Box 32)
    - draft ink sketch (Box 32)
    - pencil drafts, 8p. (Box 32)
  - "Books make the home":
    - ink and pencil draft (Box 32)
    - oversize printed copy (Mapcase 13V-F-09)
    - small printed copy, 2p. (Box 32)
  - C.I.O.-I.W.O.: ink drafts, 8p. (Box 32)
  - [The Capitol]: pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 32)
  - oversize Carnegie Institute (Pittsburgh, PA.): printed copy (Mapcase 13V-F-09)
  - Chicago Council of American-Soviet Friendship: "Let us have peace" lecture by Rockwell Kent-23 printed copy, November 1957 (Box 32)
  - Defense bond minute man: pencil drafts, 5p. (Box 32)
  - "Democracy...defend it!":
    - pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 32)
    - watercolor and ink sketch (Box 32)
  - oversize "The duty to fight with all that is in us...":
    - ink and wash sketch (Box 32)
    - pencil sketch (Box 32)
  - [eagle]:
    - ink and pencil sketch (Box 32)
    - pencil draft oversize (Mapcase 13V-F-09)
  - "Equal and exact justice to all...;" pencil draft of lettering (Mapcase 13V-F-09)
  - "Europe":
    - ink and pencil draft (Box 32)
    - pencil drafts, 4p. (Box 32)
    - pencil sketch (Box 32)
  - [farmer carrying rock]:
    - charcoal, ink and paint sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-09)
    - pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 32)
  - Forest Fire Fighters Service:
    - ink sketches, 3p. (Box 32)
    - pencil drafts, 11p. (Box 32)
    - pencil sketches, 9p. (Box 32)
  - "Free Morris Schappes" [1941]: pencil drafts, 9p. (Box 32)
  - "Give the money that has been spent in war;" pencil drafts (Box 32)
  - "Heil, Hitler!":
    - ink and wash sketch (Box 33)
    - pencil draft (Box 33)
  - "In which we serve":
    - pencil drafts. 3p. (Box 33)
    - oversize pencil drafts, 2p. (Mapcase 13V-F-09)
    - oversize pencil sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-09)
  - Kent, Rockwell-Congressional campaign: pencil draft (Box 33)
  - "Life, liberty and the pursuit of happiness;" pencil draft of lettering (Box 33)
  - The Marchof Dimes:
    - pencil drafts, 7p. (Box 33)
    - watercolor draft (Box 33)
  - oversize Nana (drama): printed copy (Mapcase 13V-F-09)
  - National Council to Combat Blindness:
    - ink and pencil draft (Box 33)
    - pencil drafts, 8p. (Box 33)
    - watercolor & pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 33)
  - oversize National Educational Alliance: pencil sketch with clippings, mock-up, 7p. (Mapcase 13V-F-09)
  - "On earth peace":
    - ink sketch (Box 33)
    - pencil draft (Box 33)
    - pencil drafts (lettering), 2p. (Box 33)
  - "Out of this peace, sinews of war;" pencil draft (Box 33)
  - "Produce for victory;" watercolor and charcoal sketch (Box 33)
  - Russian war relief:
    - ink and pencil draft (Mapcase 13V-F-09)
    - pencil drafts, 4p. (Box 33)
  - Russian war relief-"Clothes for Russia":
    - ink lettering (Box 33)
    - oversize pencil draft (Mapcase 13V-F-09)
    - oversize red and black ink lettering (with printed illus.) (Mapcase 13V-F-09)
  - Russian war relief-"Give for medical aid!;" printed scroll (Box 33)
  - Russian war relief-"Give seed to Russia;" pencil drafts, 5p. (Box 33)
  - [Spanish Civil War] "Save the children of Spain;" pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 33)
  - oversize [Spanish Civil War] "That Spain's children May live;" 2 printed copies oversize (Box 33)
  - [sentry]:
    - charcoal and wash sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-09)
    - pencil drafts (Box 33)
  - "Stop Hitler":
    - ink tracing (Box 33)
    - pencil drafts, 6p. (Box 33)
    - pencil sketch (Box 33)
  - Student Christian Association Movement:
    - ink sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-09)
    - oversize two printed copies (Mapcase 13V-F-09)
  - "That, for their sake ...;" watercolor sketch (Box 33)
  - oversize "This we have not understood ...;" pencil draft " (Mapcase 13V-F-09)
  - To all Fascists":
    - pencil drafts, 5p. (Box 33)
    - 2 printed copies (Box 33)
  - U.S.S.:
    - pencil drafts, 8p. (Box 33)
    - oversize pencil drafts, 2p. (Mapcase 13V-F-09)
  - Volunteers for peace: pencil drafts, 3p. (Box 33)
  - "We hold these truths to be self-evident;" pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 33)
  - "1 out of 8;" pencil drafts, 3p. (Box 33)
  - "1775-1936" [Vermont Marble Workers' Strike]: (Box 33)
    - proof (incomplete) Re. Meeting in New York (Box 33)
  - oversize charcoal and pencil sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-09)
  - ink and pencil draft (Box 33)
  - oversize ink and pencil draft (Mapcase 13V-F-09)
  - pencil drafts, 49p. (Box 33)
  - oversize pencil drafts and sketches, 12p. (Mapcase 13V-F-09)
  - pencil lettering, 2p. (Box 33)
  - pencil sketches (Box 33)
- Series XI: Other Categories
  - Borders:
    - Cocktail menu:
      - ink sketch (Box 34)
      - pencil draft (Box 34)
    - ink and pencil draft (Box 34)
    - pencil drafts, 7p. (Box 34)
  - Calendars:
    - [ages of man]: pencil drafts, 10p. (Box 34)
    - oversize [agricultural workers]: pencil drafts (Mapcase 13V-F-06)
    - Colby College engagement calendar-1973 printed copy (December illustration is "Monhegan" by Kent) (Box 34)
    - The Metropolitan Museum of Art:
      - Birthday Book [c1984]: printed copy (3 August illus. is "Moby Dick" by Kent) (Box 34)
      - Birthday Book [c1985]: printed copy (21 June illus. is "Winter" by Kent) (Box 34)
    - woodblock print, 1926 (Box 34)
    - pencil drafts, 7p. (Box 34)
  - Chinaware design: